all right well please turn to page 85 in
好的，请转到第85页
your class notes and in this hour our
你的班级笔记，在这一小时我们的
topic is the purpose of biblical
话题是圣经的目的
counseling the Gospel of Matthew closes
辅导马太福音结束
with what has often been called the
通常被称为
Great Commission there Jesus tells his
那里的大使命耶稣告诉他
eleven disciples to go therefore and
十一个门徒因此而去
make disciples of all the nations this
让所有国家的门徒都这样做
is our purpose in the church age to make
是我们在教会时代的目的
disciples in this idea of making
弟子这个想法制作
disciples which includes starting with
门徒，包括开始
the gospel and then specific
福音然后具体
discipleship working through specific
门徒训练具体
issues at that point in that time with
在那个时间点与问题
our counsel ease and also general
我们的律师轻松而且一般
discipleship helping our counsel ease
门徒训练有助于我们的建议轻松自如
become proficient at the spiritual
精通精神
discipline so that they have a strong
纪律使他们有一个强大的
vibrant walk with God and are involved
充满活力地与上帝同行并参与其中
incapable of ministry as they go forward
他们前进时无能为力
these are the things that we're seeking
这些是我们正在寻求的东西
to do with each of our counsel ease
与我们的每一位律师轻松相处
similarly in a discipleship relationship
同样在门徒关系中
you're working on the discipleship side
你在门徒训练方面工作
but concurrently there are inevitably
但同时也不可避免地存在
some of those specific discipleship
一些具体的门徒训练
issues that you'll work through as well
你会通过及工作问题
so the purpose of biblical counseling is
所以圣经辅导的目的是
to make disciples there are these three
使门徒有这三个
components of discipleship in the
门徒训练的组成部分
biblical counseling room and the first
圣经咨询室和第一个
is the gospel what is the gospel if
是福音是什么福音，如果
someone asked you what must I do to be
有人问你我该做些什么
saved what would you say to them this is
保存了你对他们说的这是什么
a simple question and yet it is the most
一个简单的问题，但它是最多的
important question that anyone will ever
任何人都会遇到的重要问题
ask many people in our culture have been
在我们的文化中问过很多人
to churches or have been around
到教堂或周围
Christians and have heard many
基督徒并听过很多
unbiblical answers to that question and
不符合圣经的回答这个问题和
they've probably heard some true answers
他们可能听过一些真实的答案
to that question let's think about the
对于那个问题让我们考虑一下
complete facts of the gospel for us in
我们福音的完整事实
the biblical counseling room to
圣经的咨询室
communicate the truth about man that all
传达关于所有人的真相
have sinned and fall short of the glory
犯了罪，亏缺了荣耀 。
of God to communicate that the penalty
上帝传达那种惩罚
for sin is death and to communicate that
为罪是死亡和沟通
Jesus Christ has offered to pay that
耶稣基督已经提出要付出代价
price in their place is vital then the
价格在自己的位置是至关重要的，则
response the response of both faith in
响应双方秉着在响应
those facts and repentance a a turning
这些事实和忏悔转向
from the life of being a slave to sin to
从被罪 的奴隶生活
turning to a life of serving Jesus
转向为耶稣服务的生活
Christ as Lord is also part of the
基督作为主也是其中的一部分
required response to the gospel why does
需要回应福音的原因
this matter in the counseling room it
这个问题在咨询室呢
matters because salvation necessarily
重要的是因为救赎必然
precedes biblical counseling and
先于圣经辅导和
discipleship the unbeliever according to
根据不信教徒的门徒训练
Romans 8 6 through 8 is hostile toward
罗马人8 6到8是敌对的
God and is not able to obey his word so
上帝并没有能够顺从他的话
it won't help an unbeliever to
它不会帮助一个不信的人
understand what the Bible says about
了解圣经所说的内容
replacing anger with forgiveness because
用宽恕取代愤怒因为
he doesn't want to do that and he's not
他不想这样做而他不是
able to be a doer of the word
能成为 这个词的实干家
most importantly the biggest problem
最重要的是最大的问题
that the unbeliever has is that they're
不信的人就是他们
separated from God that's more important
与上帝隔绝， 这更重要
than the reason they came to you for
而不是他们来找你的原因
counseling so we start with the gospel
咨询所以我们从福音开始
point be under Roman numeral 2 the
点在罗马数字2下面
gospel provides some practical
福音提供了一些实用的
diagnostic questions for the counseling
咨询的诊断问题
room first
房间第一
I often ask what did you believe when
我常常问你在什么时候相信
you came to Christ for salvation here
你来到基督的救赎这里
you're engaging the council E and you're
你搞该局 E和你
finding out what exactly are they
找出他们究竟是什么
putting their trust in what do they
相信他们是什么
perceive the gospel to be
认为福音是
a second diagnostic question is this if
第二诊断问题是这样的，如果
you died and God asked you why should I
你死了，上帝问你为什么要这样做
let you into heaven
让你进入天堂
what would you say that one from
你会怎么说那个
discipleship evangelism we're going the
门徒传福音我们要去
same direction with that question aren't
与该问题相同的方向不是
we and then a third question how did
我们然后第三个问题是怎么做的
your life change after you became a
你成为后，你的生活会发生变化
Christian this one helps us find out if
基督徒这一个帮助我们找出是否
this person's understanding of a
这个人对a的理解
response to the gospel included
对福音的回应包括在内
repentance where there's some different
悔改哪里有些不同
direction of life from serving sin to
从服务罪到生命的方向
serving God
侍奉上帝
so these practical questions are helpful
所以这些实际问题很有帮助
because they help us understand better
因为它们有助于我们更好地理解
whether or not the true gospel is being
无论真正的福音是否存在
trusted for salvation and also whether
信赖救恩以及是否
this faith and repentance has been the
这种信仰和忏悔一直是
response of your counsel II well some
你的律师的反应很好一些
people who come to us every year for
每年都来找我们的人
biblical counseling
圣经辅导
are not believers they either have not
不是信徒， 他们要么没有
understood the gospel or they haven't
理解福音，或者他们没有
responded to it in faith and repentance
以信心和悔改回应它
so with each counsel II at the beginning
所以每个律师都在一开始
I explained the gospel and I asked them
我解释了福音，我问他们
what their response has been and when
他们的反应是什么以及何时
what it is that night one time there was
那天晚上有一次是什么时候
a man who came for counseling who had
一个来咨询的男人
been attending our church for twelve
十二岁时我们一直在教堂
years when we went over the gospel and I
多年我们和福音一起过去了
asked him his response he said you know
问他回答他说你知道
no I have never come to Christ in that
不，我从来没有来过基督
way he said I think about it a lot a few
路上，他说，我想了很多几
times I was close but now now never made
我接近但现在从未做过
that commitment to Christ never turned
对基督的承诺从未转变过
from living for me to living forgotten
从为我而活到被遗忘的生活
this was a guy who was a church every
这是一个每个人都是教会的人
week with his family went to one of the
与他的家人每周去上的一个
small group Bible studies and he would
小组圣经研究，他会
just say well I think it's great for my
说得好我觉得这对我来说很棒
wife and kids and so I think it helps us
妻子和孩子，所以我觉得它对我们有所帮助
as a family
作为一个家庭
for me to go to your church well when
我什么时候去教堂
you think about that if I didn't have
如果我没有，你会想到这一点
that information I would be making an
那个信息我会做的
assumption that was incorrect and the
假设是不正确的
result of the assumption that this man
假设这个男人的结果
was redeemed that this man had the Holy
被救赎的是这个人有神圣的
Spirit inside of him that this man was
这个人是他内心的精神
seeking to honor God as his God wouldn't
寻求尊重上帝，因为他的上帝不会
be true and of course what this man if I
是真的，当然，如果我这个男人
made those assumptions and I was
我做了那些假设
communicating the truths of the word to
将这个词的真相传达给
help him replace sin with righteousness
帮助他用正义取代罪
we wouldn't go very far because he
我们不会走得太远，因为他
wouldn't have the Holy Spirit inside
不会有圣灵在里面
enabling him to put to death the deeds
使他能够处死他们的行为
of the flesh nor would he want to here's
肉体，他也不想在这里
a question what about this common
一个问题是什么常见的
problem professing believers who have
有自称信徒的问题
not turned from sin to a life direction
没有从罪恶转向生活方向
of honoring Christ as Lord we also get
尊重基督为主，我们也得到了
many counsel easy-chair in this group
许多律师在这个小组担任主席
they've responded to an inaccurate or
他们回应了一个不准确的或
incomplete gospel they believed in a
他们相信的福音不完整
gospel that did not include the topics
不包括主题的福音书
of sin and repentance often this is the
罪恶和悔改常常是这样的
gospel they hear at the church they
福音他们在教堂里听到了他们
attend so this counsel Lee is still a
参加这样的律师李仍然是一个
slave to sin and they're living as
罪恶的奴隶，他们的生活
slaves to sin because they have not been
奴隶是因为他们没有犯罪
born again these people come to you
这些人再次出生来找你
confused because they go to church and
因为他们去教堂而感到困惑
they've responded to what they've heard
他们回应了他们所听到的
as the gospel at their church and so
作为他们教会的福音等等
they think they are Christians but they
他们认为他们是基督徒，但他们
know that they're still slaves to sin
知道他们仍然是犯罪的奴隶
it's confusing how can these two things
令人困惑的是这两件事怎么样
be going on that's why it's so important
继续这就是为什么它如此重要
for us to begin with the gospel these
我们从这些福音开始
two key passages provide biblical
两个关键段落提供圣经
solutions for this type of counseling
这种咨询的解决方案
Romans 6:4 through 14 clearly describes
罗马书6：4到14清楚地描述了
that coming to
来了
saving faith includes dying to sin so
拯救信仰包括死于罪恶
we'll open our Bibles to Romans 6 and
我们将把我们的圣经开给罗马书6章和
we'll read Romans 6 four through 14
我们将阅读罗马书6章4到14节
together and then I ask the council a
在一起，然后我问理事会一个
have you ever come to Christ in the way
你有没有在路上来到基督面前
that's described here in that passage
这段经文中描述的内容
you have the concept that the person who
你有这个人的概念
has come to Christ is immersed in Christ
已经来到基督沉浸在基督里
and also immersed in his death the
而且还沉浸在他的死亡之中
person who has become a Christian has
已经成为基督徒的人
died with Christ they have died to sin
与基督同死， 他们已经死于罪
and the passage concludes with the idea
这段经文以这个想法结束
of what we as Christians should think
我们作为基督徒应该怎么想
about ourselves now I am dead to sin but
关于我们自己现在我死了，但是
I am alive to God in Christ Jesus for
我在基督耶稣里为上帝而活着
this for this type of counsel II seeing
对于这种类型的律师我看到了这一点
a passage like that is vital because
这样的一段是至关重要的，因为
they realize you know I haven't ever
他们知道你知道我还没有过
died to sin I know that I wanted to go
死的罪，我知道我想去
to heaven I believe the facts of the
天堂我相信的事实
gospel but I haven't died to sin
福音，但我没有死于罪
nothing's really changed that's helpful
什么都没有改变，这是有帮助的
another helpful diagnostic or helpful
另一个有用的诊断或帮助
passage with corresponding questions as
通过相应的问题作为
Romans 8:6 through 13 and in there we'll
罗马书8：6到13，我们在那里
read that together and then ask the one
一起读， 然后问一个
question which one are you referring to
问你指的是哪一个
the passages a clear description of
这段经文清楚地描述了
those who live in the flesh the unsaved
那些谁住在肉体的未保存
and those who live by the spirit of the
那些依靠精神生活的人
Christian this really is big in our
基督徒这 对我们来说真的很重要
culture because when you think about it
文化， 因为当你想到它
when those poles come out and 86% of
当那些杆子出来时86％的杆子
Americans believe that they are
美国人相信他们是
Christians in the practical day-to-day
基督徒在实际的日常生活中
living and the conversations you have
生活和你的谈话
with probably the hundred people in your
可能你的一百个人
life and probably eighty six of them
生活，其中可能有八十六个
have not come to Christ and responded to
还没有来基督，并回答了
the gospel in faith and repentance so
信仰和悔改 的福音所以
many of those we see as counsel ease we
许多我们认为可以缓解我们的建议
start with the gospel what could be more
从福音开始可能更多
important than that and what a great joy
比这更重要，多么快乐
there is when
有时间
and somebody hears the gospel and God
有人听到了福音和上帝
does what only he can do he convicts
做他唯一可以做的事就是他定罪
their heart of sin he speaks to their
他们的罪恶之心与他们说话
heart and their response to the gospel
心和他们对福音的回应
that night in your office is faith and
那天晚上在你的办公室是信仰和
repentance praise God for those times we
在我们这些时候悔改赞美上帝
have those every year at the valley
那些每年都在山谷
Bible Counseling Center well Roman
圣经咨询中心罗马
numerals three and four
数字三和四
our specific discipleship and general
我们具体的门徒训练和一般
discipleship if a council Lea is born
如果一个理事会Lea出生，那就是门徒训练
again they are capable of becoming
他们又有能力成为
disciples so these next two sections of
门徒这么接下来的两节
our study address the two components of
我们的研究解决了两个组成部分
helping somebody become a strong
帮助某人成为一个强者
disciple in our study tonight I'm going
我们今晚的研究中的弟子我要去了
to use the terms specific discipleship
使用术语特定的门徒训练
and general discipleship to describe two
和一般的门徒训练描述两个
different aspects of the purpose of
不同方面的目的
biblical counseling which is making
正在制作的圣经辅导
disciples I'm going to call specific
门徒我打算打电话给具体的
discipleship a particular need for help
门徒训练特别需要帮助
from God's Word to deal with
从上帝的话来处理
circumstances or heart issues in a
情况或心脏问题
god-honoring way so here there's a
敬神的方式所以这里有一个
particular need or problem in the
特别需要或问题
council 'is life and they need to
理事会'是生命，他们需要
understand what the scriptures say about
了解经文所说的内容
that
那
so that's specific discipleship it comes
所以这是具体的门徒说到
in different forms first thessalonians
以不同的形式首先是萨洛森人
5:14 has three categories one is sin so
5:14有三个类别，一个是罪
in regard to sin we help the Christian
关于罪，我们帮助基督徒
replace sin with righteousness another
用正义取代另一个罪
is the person who's faint-hearted this
是谁的缩头乌龟此人
could be the image for a believer who
可能是一个信徒的形象
really doesn't know the promises of
真不知道的承诺
God's Word or the truth of it that
上帝的话语或者它的真相
address this matter in their life so we
在他们的生活中解决这个问题所以我们
strengthen them through the scriptures
通过经文强化它们
and then the person who's weak they
然后是那些弱者的人
might be weak in their trust in God or
他们对上帝或他们的信任可能很弱
they might be weak in their
他们可能会很弱
understanding of the applications of
理解应用程序
God's Word so whether the problem is sin
上帝的话语， 所以问题是否是罪
or faint-hearted or weak the solution is
解决方案是胆小或弱
in the word
在这个词
and this detailed study of what the word
并详细研究了这个词
says about the circumstances the hard
说到困难的情况
issues involved in their response this
参与他们的反应这个问题
is specific discipleship I'm defining
是我所定义的特定门徒
general discipleship as the practices
一般门徒训练作为实践
taught in the Bible is necessary for
在圣经中教导是必要的
maintenance of godliness and for growth
保持敬虔和成长
in spiritual maturity so specific
在精神成熟中如此具体
discipleship enables a Christian to
门徒训练使基督徒能够
biblically handle a particular
圣经处理一个特定的
circumstance in life and general
生活中的环境和一般情况
discipleship includes the Bible's
门徒训练包括圣经
methods for increasing obedience to God
增加服从上帝的方法
it's kind of like this if we used the
如果我们使用它，它就像这样
example of money specific discipleship
特定于金钱的门徒训练的例子
would be getting somebody to stop
会让某人停下来
spending $300 a week betting on football
投注足球每周花费300美元
and general discipleship would be
一般的门徒训练将是
helping this guy and his wife develop a
帮助这个家伙和他的妻子发展
realistic budget and live by it if it
现实的预算，如果它生活
was if it was hare here's one for you
如果它是野兔这里是你的一个
ladies if we was here it would be
如果各位我们在这里将是
specific discipleship would be whatever
具体的门徒训练将是什么
stuff you put on your hair to correct a
你戴在头发上的东西来纠正一个
really bad problem and general
非常糟糕的问题和一般
discipleship would be just the things
门徒训练就是事物
that you put in your hair to keep it
你把头发留在头发里
healthy and full looking all the time so
健康，充满期待所有的时间，所以
okay
好的
I'm an expert on that topic okay
我在这方面的专家好吗
so you get the picture if it was your
所以如果是你的话你会得到照片
body specific discipleship would be
身体特定的门徒训练将是
you've got a compound fracture a bone is
你有一个骨头复合骨折
broken and it's sticking out of the skin
破了，它从皮肤里伸出来
specific discipleship is the doctor
具体的门徒训练是医生
setting it and putting it in a cast a
设置它，并把它在一个铸件的
general discipleship is you go to the
一般的门徒训练是你去的
gym three times a week and you eat
健身房三次，一个星期，你吃
healthy foods that sort of thing so so
健康的食物，这样的事情
there's our picture of these two things
这是我们对这两件事的看法
okay both are necessary to equip mature
好的，都有必要装备成熟
disciples of Christ so let's let's go
基督的门徒让我们走了
over to page 86 and Roman numeral three
到第86页和罗马数字三
and let's look at this thing we're
让我们来看看这件事
calling specific discipleship in some
在一些人中称特定的门徒训练
more detail specific discipleship is
更详细的具体门徒训练是
needed for the solving of three general
需要解决三个一般问题
types of problems those are overcoming
那些克服的问题类型
sin growing in wisdom and dealing with
罪恶在智慧中成长并与之打交道
trials any person who comes to you for
审判任何来找你的人
discipleship or counseling well they
他们的门徒训练或辅导
might need help in one of those things
其中一个可能需要帮助
or two or maybe even all three so first
或者两个，甚至可能全部三个
let's consider how do we accomplish the
让我们考虑一下我们如何实现这一目标
purpose of making disciples for the
为门徒做门徒的目的
Christian who commits a particular sin
犯下特定罪的基督徒
that is either serious or habitual in
这是严肃的还是习惯性的
nature there's our passage psalm 119
大自然有我们的段落诗篇119
verses 9 through 11 how can a young man
第9节到第11节一个年轻人怎么样
keep his way pure by keeping it
通过保持它保持纯粹的方式
according to your word with all my heart
根据你的话，我全心全意
I have sought you do not let me wander
我求你不要让我徘徊
from your Commandments your word I have
从你的诫命我的话
treasured in my heart that I may not sin
在我心中珍惜我可能不会犯罪
against you we see in this passage the
反对你， 我们在这段经文中看到了
glorious hope that we have as Christians
我们作为基督徒的光荣希望
the Word of God is sufficient to equip
神的话语足以装备
you and me and everybody who comes
你和我以及所有来的人
across our path who is a believer all of
在我们的道路上谁是一个信徒
us for overcoming sin for replacing sin
我们为了取代罪而克服罪
with righteousness that is our hope and
正义是我们的希望和
that's why the Word of God has to be the
这就是为什么上帝的话必须成为
only source of our count
只是我们统计的来源
at the end of each case it is such a joy
在每个案件结束时， 它是如此的快乐
when you look back with this person
当你回头看这个人的时候
whose life has changed and you both
他的生活已经改变了双方你
rejoice together because you've seen
因为你已经看到了，所以一起欢喜
this passage lived out and you've seen
这段经文过去了，你见过
God do what only he can do that's
上帝只做他能做到的事情
exciting so what should we do with the
令人兴奋所以我们应该怎么做
word to help the person we are disciple
用来帮助我们门徒的人
in your counseling well certainly one
在你的咨询当然一个
part is to teach it we should teach the
部分是教我们应该教的
word with the authority it demands this
它要求这个权威
is the place for women to preach the
是妇女传播的地方
word you're counseling another woman
你在教另一个女人
preach the word to her men preach the
向她的男人传讲这个词
word to the men you counsel preach it
字的男人，你的律师鼓吹它
with the authority it demands as the
以它所要求的权威作为
word of the Living God according to
根据生命之神的话语
verse 10 we should also emphasize the
第10节我们也应该强调
counsel ease heart response to it is
律师缓解心脏反应是
they're going to not sin against God
他们不会犯上帝的罪
which is the conclusion in verse 11 then
这是在第11节的结论然后
they must seek God and stay focused on
他们必须寻求神和保持集中
his word in verse 10 it says they don't
他在第10节中的话说它们没有
wander from it the word tells us this in
从中徘徊这个词告诉我们这个
so many other places but James 1:25
詹姆斯1:25还有很多其他的地方
talks about the person becoming a doer
谈论成为行动者的人
of the word and the person who is a doer
这个词和作为行动者的人
of the word God blesses whatever they do
上帝这个词祝福他们所做的一切
I want each of my counsel leaves to be a
我希望我的每一份律师都能成为一名律师
doer of the word and I want God to bless
在这个词上，我希望上帝保佑
whatever they do I don't think there's a
无论他们做什么我都不认为有
bigger force in the universe for them in
他们在宇宙中拥有更大的力量
overcoming their problems and growing in
克服困难，成长
discipleship so we're emphasizing the
门徒训练，所以我们强调
council Lee's response to it we don't
理事会李对此的回应我们没有
want people who know it we want people
想要了解我们想要的人
who obey it we want people who don't
谁服从它我们想要没有的人
wander from it who seek obedience with
从中寻求顺从的人徘徊
all their heart verse 11 tells us that
他们所有的心经11节告诉我们
memorizing the word is going to be
记住这个词会是
valuable as well the phrase that's used
有价值的以及使用的短语
there is your word I have treasured in
有你珍惜我的话
my heart that I may not sin against you
我的心，我可能不会对你犯罪
one time I had a counsel he who whose
有一次，我有一个律师，他谁的
problem was anger he got angry at his
愤怒的问题是他对他生气了
boss he had got
老板他有
angry at all the other people driving
对所有其他人开车都很生气
the cars on the freeway he got angry at
高速公路上的汽车 他生气了
his wife when she sinned he got angry at
他的妻子犯了罪，他生气了
a lot of people and so this was a
很多人，所以这是一个
struggle he was an angry guy he was
奋斗他是一个愤怒的家伙
angry all the time he was he was a man
一直生气他是个男人
man he wasn't he didn't do a job where
男人他不是他没有做的工作
he was sitting at a computer and
他坐在电脑前和
thinking about words all day no offense
整天思考单词没有冒犯
guys who do that okay but you know he he
球员谁做的不错，但你知道他，他
worked with his hands he worked with
他曾与他合作过
steel in high-rise buildings he was that
他是高层建筑中的钢铁
kind of a guy he was the kind of guy who
他是那种家伙的那种人
would leave super early so he could be
会超级早离开，所以他可以
at work every day like 45 minutes early
每天的工作像45分钟早
just so he'd never be late well for this
所以他永远不会迟到
guy since words weren't his thing things
因为言语不是他的事情
like journals are writing about
就像期刊写的一样
applications not possible not happening
应用程序不可能不会发生
I asked him to do that one week and he
我让他做了一个星期和他
came back with this one page that had
回来了这一页
about 12 words on it
大约12个字就可以了
and he said it took me 45 minutes so I
他说，我花了45分钟所以我
realized that's not helping him but this
意识到除了这个之外没有帮助他
thing this treasuring the word in in his
这件事在他身上珍惜这个词
heart it was everything what this guy
心里一切都是这个家伙
did he memorized 6 verses that's all but
他记得6节经文就是这样
he threw all the different verses on
他把所有不同的经文都扔了
anger he he picked the 6 that hit the
愤怒他，他选择了6击中了
nail on the head for the things he
为他的事情钉在头上
struggled with why he got angry he'd
为什么他生气他 挣扎
memorized those he reviewed him in the
记住那些他在评论他的人
car every day on his way to work in his
车途中 ， 每天在他的工作
45 minutes waiting for 7 o'clock he
45分钟等待7点，他
would review those with the Lord and he
会和主和他一起回顾那些
would think about each one with God how
会想到每一个与上帝如何
can I do this today
我今天能这样做吗？
what kind of things are going on that
什么样的事情会在该
are unresolved what happened with my
尚未解决发生了什么事我
boss yesterday how can I Oh BAE what
老大昨天我怎么能哦BAE什么的
you're saying about anger here and that
你在这里和那里说的是愤怒
was it
是吗
I mean it's it's 12 years later he's not
我的意思是它是12年后他不是
an angry guy by God's grace he developed
他发展了上帝恩典的愤怒的家伙
a habit pattern of righteousness and to
正义和习惯的习惯模式
this day if you go up and like sock him
这一天， 如果你上去，喜欢袜子他
in the arm or something he'll think of
在他的手臂或他会想到的东西
three of those verses and he won't get
其中三节经文他不会得到
angry
愤怒
I'll bring them next month you can try
我会带他们下个月你可以试试
it out okay yeah so so this is an
好吧是的，所以这是一个
important thing
重要的事情
psalm 119:11 is true and and we should
诗篇119：11是真的，我们应该
believe it's true and get our counsel
相信这是真的，并得到我们的忠告
ease to memorize the word the scriptures
容易记住经文这个词
are essential for making disciples by
对于制造门徒至关重要
enabling Christians to overcome sin one
使基督徒胜过罪一个
of the things that you receive today
你今天收到的东西
when you when you walked in was a sample
当你走进去的时候是一个样本
of a journal with scripture we use these
我们使用这些有经文的期刊
in our counseling center if you go to
如果你去我们的咨询中心
live the word squarespace.com that's
住squarespace.com这个词
written somewhere in your outline you
在你的提纲写的地方你
can you know you can get a number of
你能知道你可以获得一些
these but I just want you to see how a
这些，但我只是想让你看看如何
tool like this works the focal point of
像这样的工具是焦点
this is the Word of God in its
这就是上帝的话语
application so in this case here we have
应用程序，以便在这里这种情况下，我们有
anger we have wisdom on anger section 1
愤怒我们对愤怒第1部分有智慧
wisdom on anger section 2 so these are
愤怒部分2的智慧所以这些是
sections of groups of verses from
来自的几节经文
Proverbs each dealing with anger its
每个谚语都是愤怒的
cause what to replace it with all
导致什么用所有替换它
different facts and truths from God
来自上帝的不同事实和真理
about anger and then the third section
关于愤怒，然后是第三部分
of scripture is replacing anger
经文正在取代愤怒
particular scriptures to talk about how
特别的经文谈论如何
we replace anger with righteousness and
我们用正义取代愤怒和
what we're doing instead of becoming
我们现在所做的，而不是 成为
angry so what I ask people to do is if
生气所以我请人做的是，如果
I'm working with somebody who likes
我和一个喜欢的人一起 工作
words better than the guy who's talking
比说话的人更好的话
about before what I do is I give them
在我做什么之前就是我给他们
this and so each day they're looking
这一天他们每天都在寻找
through either all the scriptures in
通过所有的经文
section 1 or section 2 or section 3
第1节或第2节或第3节
they're looking through all those and
他们希望通过所有那些和
they're thinking about how those address
他们正在考虑如何解决这些问题
the heart issues the circumstances the
在心脏问题的情况下，
relationships in their life so they're
他们生活中的关系，所以他们是
they're evaluating all these things that
他们正在评估所有这些事情，
have to do with their anger based on the
与他们的愤怒有关
scriptures then every day I'm having
然后我每天都有经文
them fill out the
他们填写了
her journal take a look at that the
她的日记看看那个
third page of this group of papers so
这组论文的第三页如此
every day my council II is writing down
我的理事会II每天都写下来
this what happened just before I was
这就是我之前发生的事情
tempted to get angry so this person who
诱惑生气所以这个人是谁
struggles with anger is thinking about
愤怒是想斗争
the hardest point in that day when just
那天刚才的最难点
before they were they were tempted to be
在他们被诱惑之前
angry what happened so they write that
生气发生了什么，所以他们写了
down and then they what what did they
然后他们是什么做了他们
think okay what thoughts went through my
想想我的想法是什么
mind when that happened they write that
当发生这种情况时， 他们会写下来
down what emotions were they feeling was
他们的感受是什么
going on inside what were the feelings
在里面发生了什么感受
at that and they write that down too and
在那，他们也写下来了
then the next thing well when they were
然后接下来就好了
tempted to choose anger what did they do
他们试图选择愤怒他们做了什么
and say so now we're finding out their
并且这样说现在我们发现了他们的
response to the temptation something
回应诱惑的东西
happened
发生
they're tempted to become angry what did
他们很想生气
they do and what did they say they write
他们这样做， 他们说他们写的是什么
that down now the next thing they write
现在他们写下了下一件事
is what Bible verse best describes my
这是圣经经文最能描述我的
response and they know lots of Bible
回应，他们知道很多圣经
verses that have to do with anger
与愤怒有关的经文
because they read through them every day
因为他们每天都在阅读
so they pick out the verse that best
所以他们挑选出最好的经文
describes their response whether it was
描述了它们的反应是否存在
a response that honored God or a
一个尊重上帝或一个人的回应
response that was sinned against God and
响应这是得罪了神，
then they write down what was the right
然后他们写下了什么是正确的
thing to do
要做的事情
including scripture those last two
包括最后两个经文
answers are the same as they did the
答案和他们做的一样
right thing but if they didn't now
正确的事情， 但如果他们现在没有
they're thinking through how the
他们正在思考如何
scriptures address the sinful response
经文解决了罪恶的反应
and how scriptures addressed the
以及经文如何解决这个问题
righteous response and then every day
正义的反应，然后每一天
they pray and they give thanks for God's
他们祈祷，他们感谢上帝
help to replace anger with righteousness
帮助用正义取代愤怒
if they did well and if it was another
如果他们做得好，如果是另一个
day where they sinned by becoming angry
他们因生气而犯罪的那一天
they confessed that sin and repent well
他们承认了罪并且悔改得很好
think of how helpful this is for them
想想这对他们有多大帮助
because after a while after a week or
因为经过一周或一段时间后
two your counsel Lee has has something
两个你的律师李有什么东西
going on when the when the car cuts in
当汽车切入时，继续进行
front of them on the freeway they're
他们在高速公路上面前是他们的
thinking oh I'm gonna be writing about
想哦，我会写的
this later on
这个以后
and then what do they think next Oh what
然后他们接下来想什么哦什么
Bible verses talk about my two choices
圣经经文谈论我的两个选择
right here is that helpful I think
我认为 这是有用的
that's helpful and then they have a
这是有帮助的，然后他们有一个
choice and if they choose you know to be
选择，如果他们选择你知道
angry at that guy well then they're
对那个家伙很生气然后他们就是
writing about it later and that night
在晚些时候和那天晚上写下来
there praying and confessing their sin
在那里祈祷并承认自己的罪
and repenting and if they choose no Lord
如果他们不选择主 ，就悔改
it matters more to me to bring glory and
对我来说更重要的是带来荣耀和
honor to you here and they don't get
在这里尊敬你，他们没有得到
angry you know they're thinking about
生气你知道他们在考虑
the scriptures and they're obeying
经文，他们是顺从的
because their purpose is to obey God's
因为他们的目的是服从上帝的
Word and honor him this is helpful it's
言语和荣誉他这是有帮助的
helpful for them and it's helpful for
对他们有帮助，这对他们很有帮助
you I mean think about this the angry
你我的意思是想想这个生气
counsel II that you're a little afraid
律师二，你有点害怕
of when they walk in every week right
当他们每个星期都走路的时候
because you don't know but the angry
因为你不知道但生气
counsel II is handing you seven to these
律师II正在向您递交七份
things every week
每周的事情
I mean after three weeks you read all of
我的意思是三个星期后你读完所有的
these I think you understand your
这些我认为你理解你的
counsel II pretty well don't you and
律师II不错你不和
this helps you to plan and prepare well
这有助于您做好计划和准备
so that you can teach the word that hits
这样你就可以教导命中这个词
the nail right on the head that gets to
钉在头上的钉子
the idols of the heart with your counsel
你的忠告是内心的偶像
II during your counseling sessions
II在您的咨询会议期间
together so a useful tool in this
在一起所以在这一个有用的工具
process of specific discipleship and
特定门徒训练和过程
connecting your counsel II or the person
连接你的律师II或该人
your disciple with the Word of God let's
你的门徒有上帝的话语
look at point B growing in wisdom
看看B点智慧的增长
psalm 119 verses 98 through a hundred
诗篇119节经文98到100节
this passage says your Commandments make
这段经文说你的诫命
me wiser than my enemies for they are
我比我的敌人， 因为他们更聪明
ever mine I have more insight than all
曾经我的我比 所有更多的了解
my teachers for your testimonies are my
我的老师为你的证词是我的
meditation I understand more than the
冥想我比了解更多
ages because I have observed your
年龄因为我观察过你的
precepts this is incredible hope because
戒律这是令人难以置信的希望，因为
whether your counsel II is 15 years old
你的律师II是否15岁
or 40 or 60 if they grow in wisdom if
如果他们智慧成长，或者40或60岁
they understand the truth of the word
他们理解这个词的真实性
this is the result this is the great
这是结果，这是伟大的
result
结果
they will be wiser than their enemies
他们会比他们的敌人更聪明
have more insight than their teachers
比他们的老师有更多的洞察力
and understand more than people have
和理解以上的人有
lived a lot longer well that's good
生活得更久，这很好
so there's powerful hope for the
所以有强大的希望
Christian that comes to you for help
基督徒来找你帮忙
with any kind of problem
有任何问题
what can let's think about how we can
什么可以让我们思考如何做到
help equip our counsel ease to really
帮助装备我们的忠告真的很容易
understand the word well I'd like us to
理解这个词我想要我们
take a minute or two to look at page 89
花一两分钟看第89页
and the books that are listed under
和下面列出的书籍
resources I'm going to show you just a
资源我要告诉你一个
couple of them and show you why these
他们几个并告诉你为什么这些
are helpful resources for you as a
对你来说是有用的资源
counselor one there are a couple of
辅导员一个有几个
these books called quick scripture
这些书称为快速经文
reference guides there's one for
参考指南有一个
counseling women by Patricia Miller
Patricia Miller为女性提供咨询
she's a great lady who lives in Kansas
她是一位住在堪萨斯州的伟大女士
City there's one the general one the
城市有一个一般的
very first one by John Cruz this guy was
第一个是约翰克鲁兹这个家伙
a pastor for many years he's now 95
多年的牧师，他现在95
years old and what he does in his spare
岁了，他在他的余下做了什么
time is he goes to the VA hospital three
时间是他去VA医院三
times a week and shares the gospel with
每周一次并分享福音
men but what these two people have done
男人，但这两个人做了什么
is they have arranged topical
他们是否安排了热门话题
collections of Scripture so if if ladies
圣经的集合所以，如果女士们
if you're working with a lady who's
如果你和一位女士一起工作的话
struggling with communication or speech
与沟通或言语斗争
she has about ten different aspects of
她有十个不同的方面
that struggle and scriptures that
那个斗争和经文
address each of them if she's not sure
如果她不确定，请解决每个问题
about how to determine God's will there
关于如何确定上帝的意志
are scriptures to describe that if she's
是经文来形容如果她是
struggling with health issues here are
在这里努力解决健康问题
scriptures that describe that and so
描述这一点的经文
forth these are really helpful they help
这些 对他们的帮助非常有帮助
you - they help you to consider
你- 他们帮助你考虑
everything the scripture says on a topic
经文在一个主题上所说的一切
so that you can most accurately
这样你才能最准确
communicate what's necessary to your
告诉你什么是必要的
particular counsel one of the great
特别忠告其中一位伟大的人
resources that we have available to us
我们必须提供给我们的资源
is systematic theology
是系统神学
if if you've never read a systematic
如果你从未读过系统的话
theology I have a couple of examples
神学我有几个例子
here systematic theologies are really
这里有系统神学
just topical studies a systematic
只是专题研究系统性的
theology is taking everything the Bible
神学正在把圣经当作一切
says about one particular thing and
谈到一件特别的事情
putting it all together in one place for
把它们放在一个地方
you this is the kind of thing that is
你是这样的
helpful in preparation for counseling
有助于准备咨询
some of them are super detailed like the
其中一些是非常详细的
moody handbook of theology by Paul ends
保罗结束了喜怒无常的神学手册
and he has he has a lot of detail and he
他有很多细节和他
gives you a lot of information and a lot
给你很多信息和很多
of scripture on each topic and then
关于每个主题的经文然后
there are others like this one is by
还有其他像这样的人
Robert Lightner a handbook for
Robert Lightner的手册
evangelical theology and these are all
福音派神学，这些都是
written in there on page 89 this one is
在第89页写的那个是
more basic he covers a lot of ground in
更基本的他涵盖了很多方面
a shorter period of time it's
更短的时间段是
interesting because in some ways it's
有趣，因为在某些方面它是
easier reading but it's also interesting
更容易阅读，但它也很有趣
because you realize that he had to study
因为你意识到他必须学习
enough to write this only he only wrote
足以写这个只有他才写的
this so he's using his words in a more
这样他就更多地使用他的话了
concise and precise way what's the best
什么是最好的简洁而精确的方式
way to use resources like this here's my
有效运用资源， 这样 ，这里是我
suggestion
建议
get a few that you trust that your
得到一些你信任的人
pastor or elders would say you know
牧师或长老会说你知道
those are solid those are accurate and
那些是坚实的那些是准确的
then look through the same topic in two
然后在两个中查看相同的主题
or three different ones and compare
或三个不同的和比较
great opportunities to strengthen the
加强的好机会
theological foundation of our Council
我们理事会的神学基础
and also to have a more thorough
而且还要更彻底
understanding of particular issues that
了解特定问题
relate to the the topics at hand with
与手头的主题有关
our council ease one other book that's
我们的理事会放松了另外一本书
really helpful is this one by Donald
唐纳德真的很有帮助
Whitney
惠特尼
it's called spiritual disciplines for
这就是所谓的精神学科的
the Christian life dr. Whitney
基督徒生活博士。惠特尼
summarizes a lifetime of studying and
总结了一生的学习和
discipleship in this book but he covers
本书中的门徒训练， 但他涵盖了
a lot of the basics of the the spiritual
很多精神的基础知识
disciplines that you and I want to help
你和我想要帮助的纪律
our our counsel he's become proficient
我们的忠告他已经精通了
in
在
so some good resources there are more
所以一些好的资源还有更多
resources listed at BCD a socal org
在BCD上列出的社会 组织资源
here's an important idea when assigning
分配时这是一个重要的想法
any of these kinds of resources that
这些资源中的任何一种
we've looked at or those you create and
我们看过 你或者你创造的那些
I encourage you create good biblical
我鼓励你创造良好的圣经
counseling resources and share them with
咨询资源并与之分享
the rest of us but when you do that it's
我们其他人，但是当你这样做的时候
important to communicate in a way that
以某种方式沟通很重要
focuses on the Scriptures and obedience
专注于圣经和顺从
to the scriptures not on what you said
经文不是你说的
or what that person said in that book
或那个人在那本书中所说的话
not the words or the expressions of the
不是单词或 的表达式
writers but but on the Word of God
作家，但在上帝的话语
itself that's that's the source of
本身就是这个的来源
growing lean wisdom that's the source of
不断增长的精益智慧是其源泉
overcoming sin the third major need for
克服罪恶的第三个主要需要
specific discipleship is for the
具体的门徒训练是为了
Christian who's struggling with
克里斯蒂安正在努力奋斗
adversity look at point-c on page 86 and
逆境看第86页的点-c和
that is dealing with trials dealing with
这是处理试验处理
trials psalm 119:105 107 109 110 and 112
psalm 119：105 107 109 110和112
say this your word is a lamp to my feet
说这个，你的话就是我的脚
and a light to my path I am exceedingly
我极其轻松地走向我的道路
afflicted revive me O Lord according to
受灾Ø根据神复活我
your word my life is continually in my
你的话我的生活一直在我的生活中
hand yet I do not forget your law the
但我不忘记你的法律
wicked have laid a snare for me yet I
邪恶的我已经为我制造了 一个网罗
have not gone astray from your precepts
并没有偏离你的戒律
I have inherited your testimonies
我继承了你的见证
forever for they are the joy of my heart
永远因为他们是我心中的快乐
I have inclined my heart to perform your
我倾心于表达你的意志
statutes forever even to the end this
法规永远到最后这个
describes what we're working toward with
描述了我们正在努力的方向
that person that we're disciple in your
那个我们是你的弟子的人
counseling in the midst of adversity and
在逆境和堕落期间提供咨询
the writer of this psalm is in the midst
这首诗的作者正在中间
of adversity let's look at the three
逆境让我们看看这三个
sections first verse 105
第一节105节
hope due to the power of God's word his
希望由于 上帝的话语他的力量
word will transform this confusing and
这句话会改变这种令人困惑的
difficult season of hardship into an
困难的季节困难变成了
easily understood set of circumstances
容易理解的情况
it's turning the light on all of a
它正在全力以赴
sudden it's not so confusing and obscure
突然间它不那么令人困惑和模糊
anymore your friend sees it all clearly
你的朋友已经清楚地看到了这一切
because of the truth of God's Word his
因为上帝的话语的真相
word will not only illumine the
字不仅照亮了
circumstances the difficulty but also
情况困难但也
will show your counsel II the way to go
将向你的律师II展示前进的方向
your part is overseeing that process you
你的部分是监督你的过程
must absolutely trust and believe that
必须绝对信任并相信
God will do his part he will cause the
神会做他的一部分，他将导致
word to be light in your counsel ease
在你的忠告轻松的话
life believe that that's true and then
生活相信那是真的然后
communicate clearly the Scriptures
清楚地传达圣经
addressing the counsel ease problem your
解决你的问题缓解问题
metaphorically speaking walking with
比喻说走路
them down this road toward obeying the
他们沿着这条路走向顺从
word and trusting the word the second
单词并信任第二个单词
section is verses 107 109 and 110 this
部分是107 109和110节
person is extremely afflicted he says in
他说，人是极度折磨的
verse 107 but the choice that he makes
第107节，但他做出的选择
could result in the extension of his
可能导致他的延期
life or the end of it
生命或它的结束
according to verse 109 and then there's
根据第109节，然后是
also 110 evil people are intentionally
也有110个邪恶的人故意
trying to trap him so along these lines
试图 沿着这些方向 陷阱他
ask your counsel to describe their
请你的律师描述他们的
particular hardships listen understand
特别艰辛听听懂
care about what's going on with them but
关心他们发生了什么，但是
then bring them back to this person in
然后把它们带回给这个人
psalm 119
诗篇119
what is the psalmist's response to this
什么是诗人对此的回应
adversity first he asks God to revive
逆境首先他要求上帝复活
him in verse 107 he is seeking the Lord
他在诗歌107，他正寻求 主
strength to survive and then even when
生存的力量， 甚至是什么时候
his life is on the line he does not
他的生活是他没有行
forget God's Word
忘记上帝的话语
according to verse 109 teacher accounts
根据109节教师的说法
will lead to do that
会导致这样做
and then in verse 110 even in the midst
然后在第110节，即使在中间
of this intense danger and people out to
这种强烈的危险和人们的关注
get him he does not go astray from
让他他不迷路走
obeying the scriptures think about that
服从经文就是这么想的
there's a temptation to be focused on
有一种被关注的诱惑
what they're doing to try to get me
他们正在做什么来试图让我
right now but instead he has to be
现在， 但他必须是
somewhat aware of that but his main
有点意识到这一点，但他的主要
focus is not going astray from obeying
专注不会因服从而误入歧途
the scriptures here's my circumstance
这里的经文是我的情况
people are out to get me
人们出去找我
what must I do to obey the word here and
我必须做些什么来遵守这里的话
now this is the formula for your
现在这是你的公式
disciples in your counsel ease who are
你的律师中的门徒可以轻松自如
struggling with hard times the third and
第三次和第三次艰苦挣扎
final section of this passage describes
本段的最后一节描述
the result of the decisions made in
在作出 决定的结果
verses 107 109 and 110 for this person
这个人的第107 109和110节
God's Word is his forever the Scriptures
上帝的话语永远是他的圣经
of the joy of his heart and so he
他心中的喜悦和他
positions his heart to obey God's Word
他的心脏要遵守上帝的话语
until his final breath
直到最后一口气
on earth and so it is with a good
在地球上，这是一个很好的
discipleship ministry or a good biblical
门徒的事工或圣经的好
counseling ministry if this is what
咨询部，如果这是什么
we're teaching and if this is how we are
我们正在教学，如果这是我们的方式
seeking to help our brothers and sisters
寻求帮助我们的兄弟姐妹
who are struggling we're focusing on the
谁在挣扎我们专注于
word and we're focusing on the heart
我们专注于内心
response to the word when the heart
当心脏回应这个词
response of that person that you're
那个人是你的回应
serving is as described here things go
服务就像这里所描述的那样
well they are able to deal with
他们能够应对
adversity and in the process they became
逆境，在他们成为过程中
stronger than they were before in their
强于他们在他们的前
personal walk with God because God is
个人与上帝同行，因为上帝是
our God and because his word is true
我们的上帝，因为他的话是真的
that's the normal outcome that's not the
这是正常的结果，而不是
exception and so that's what we look
例外，这就是我们的样子
forward to watching God work watching
前往观看上帝的工作观看
God change soul
上帝改变了灵魂
next Roman numeral four over on page 87
第87页的下一个罗马数字四
general discipleship this general
一般门徒训练这个将军
discipleship is also an important part
门徒训练也是一个重要的部分
of a disciple in ministry we're trying
在我们正在尝试的事工中的门徒
to lead our brother or sister to a point
带领我们的兄弟或姐妹到一个点
of maturity where they are
成熟的他们在哪里
systematically implementing the
系统地实施
applications of Scripture as a normal
将圣经作为正常的应用
pattern of life so here we have a number
生活模式所以这里我们有一个数字
of different areas where they can do
他们可以做的不同领域
that one of the questions people ask
人们问的一个问题
about this is when does discipleship end
关于这是门徒训练何时结束
does discipleship end when all these
所有这些都会使门徒训练结束
things have been covered or does it end
事情已被覆盖或结束
when the disciple he is proficient
当门徒他精通时
enough and learning and obeying that
足够的，学习和服从
they can finish the rest on their own
他们可以自己完成剩下的工作
that's really a decision for you to make
这是真正为你 做 决定
with the Lord what would best honor God
与主最好的荣耀上帝
what would best serve this person at
什么才能最好地为这个人服务
this time well every biblical counseling
这一次很好的每一次圣经辅导
case does have an aspect of discipleship
案件确实有门徒训练的一面
we want to help the person solve the
我们想帮助这个人解决问题
problem biblically but that's not the
圣经问题， 但那不是
end there's also this simultaneous
结束也有这个同时
discipleship going on I want each of my
门徒事情我想我的每一个
counsel leaves to be strong in a few of
律师在一些人​​中留下坚强的态度
these things and able to grow in the
这些事情，能够 在成长
rest of them by the time we finish
当我们完成时，其余部分
dealing with their struggle with anger
处理他们与愤怒的斗争
or whatever the problem is so let's take
或者无论问题是什么，让我们采取
a look at these categories of general
看看这些类别的一般
discipleship the first category is
门徒训练的第一类是
training disciples for interaction with
训练弟子与互动
God
神
number one study of God's Word with
数与神的话语 的一项研究
application the person who hears and
应用听到的人和
acts upon Christ's word weathers the
根据基督的话来行动
storm according to Matthew seven second
风暴根据马修七秒钟
memorization of God's Word we talked
记住我们所说的上帝的话语
about that number three the study of
关于第三的研究
theology this provides a framework so
神学这提供了一个框架
that when your disciple II or counsel II
当你的弟子II或律师II
has a good understand
很了解
the basics of theology they have this
他们有神学的基础知识
framework and now as they read through
框架，现在他们阅读
the word everyday they interpret
他们每天解释的 这个词
paragraphs and individual verses and
段落和个别经文和
individual ideas in light of this true
根据这个真实的个人观点
framework helpful accurate perception of
框架有益的准确的认识
trials this changes their perception of
试验这改变了他们的看法
the storm from bad to good they realize
他们意识到风暴从坏到好
that they are not vulnerable but rather
他们不是脆弱的，而是
this is an opportunity to prove their
这是证明他们的机会
faith and bring glory to God
信仰并将荣耀归给上帝
number five regular purposeful prayer
五号定期有目的的祷告
vital part of the Christians walk with
基督徒的重要组成部分走路
God
神
number six is worship in church this is
排名第六的是崇拜在教堂，这是
really important you cannot
真的很重要， 你做不到
underestimate the value of accurate
低估了准确的价值
preaching of the word as part of the
宣传这个词作为一部分
discipleship and growth of the people
门徒和人民的增长
you work with number seven physical
你在七号身体上工作
obedience a common topic for the
服从一个共同话题
biblical counseling room an important
圣经辅导室很重要
area of discipleship and number eight
门徒训练和八号领域
honoring God with money each of us have
用我们每个人的钱来纪念上帝
great opportunities to bring glory and
巨大的机遇带来的荣耀和
honor to God in the financial decisions
在财务决策中尊敬上帝
we make Roman numeral for general
我们为一般的罗马数字
discipleship category B the second
门徒训练B类第二
category of general discipleship topics
一般门徒话题的范畴
is training disciples for interaction
正在训练门徒进行互动
with people number one evangelism this
这是人们排名第一的传福音
is a necessary obedience for each of us
是我们每个人的必要服从
it is the Great Commission it is the
它是伟大的委员会
responsibility that we all have as
责任，我们都为
believers number two love for others
信徒们对别人有两种爱
this is the core of God's of
这是 神的核心
Christlikeness the mindset of obedience
基督化是顺服的心态
that's necessary for a habit pattern of
这对于习惯模式来说是必要的
loving every person that God has in your
爱上帝在你里面的每一个人
council these life is is vital in this
理事会这些生活在这方面至关重要
area of general discipleship and then
一般门徒训练的领域然后
number three the biblical role in the
第三个是圣经中的角色
home each of us has a huge influence
我们每个人都有巨大的影响力
upon the lives of the other people with
关于其他人的生活
in our household and the same is true of
在我们的家庭和同样是真正的
your counsel II or the person that your
你的律师或II的人，你的
disciple let's help them develop a
弟子让我们帮助他们发展一个
strong biblical understanding of their
强烈的圣经理解他们的
responsibilities in how to live those
在如何生活的责任
out and then for involvement in ministry
出来，然后在 教育部参与
I do whatever I can to introduce to
我尽我所能介绍
ministry the people who are coming to me
那些来找我的人
for help at this point let's take a look
在这一点上寻求帮助我们来看看吧
at Roman numeral five some practical
在罗马数字五有些实用
questions how does the biblical
问题如何圣经
counselor arrange simultaneous progress
辅导员安排同步进度
in both specific discipleship and
在特定的门徒训练和
general discipleship here are three
一般门徒训练在这里是三个
things that I think are helpful one
我认为有用的东西之一
through carefully planned homework you
通过精心策划的作业你
can have your council e working on
可以让你的理事会工作
specific discipleship and something else
具体的门徒训练和别的东西
in general discipleship every week that
每周一般的门徒训练
they meet with you during the time that
他们在时间与大家见面的是
council e's meet with me as much as i
Council电子与我见面，就像 我
can influence them I require them to
可以影响他们我需要他们
attend a solid church during that time
在那段时间里参加一个坚实的教堂
if what they're hearing on Sunday
如果他们周日听到的话
conflicts with what they hear when they
与他们听到的内容发生冲突
meet with you that's going to make
与你见面即将制作
change difficult and also for this idea
改变困难也是为了这个想法
of causing specific discipleship and
导致特定的门徒训练和
general discipleship to both be ongoing
一般的门徒训练都在进行中
use all the other resources of your
使用的所有其他资源的
church get this person plugged into some
教会让这个人陷入困境
ministry that they're equipped for it
他们为它配备的部门
this time have them under the authority
这次让他们处于权威之下
of the elders of your church so that
这样你教会的长老们
they can benefit from that shepherding
他们可以从牧养中受益
and oversight get them involved in a
和疏忽让他们参与进来
ministry that fits their age group or
适合他们年龄组的部门
their gifts if you have small groups or
他们的礼物，如果你有小团体或
some kind of Bible studies or if you
某种圣经研究或者如果你
have Sunday school or if you have
有星期日学校或如果你有
ministries that involve groups of people
涉及一群人的部委
working together get them involved very
一起工作让他们非常参与
important
重要
question B what must I do to become most
问题B我必须做些什么来成为最重要的
useful to guide in a disciple making
有助于指导门徒制作
ministry I don't think there's anything
我不认为有任何东西
more important than being consistent in
比一致更重要
your own personal discipleship see what
你个人的门徒训练看到了什么
resources will benefit my counsel e
资源将有利于我的顾问e
you've you've seen them already and
你们一定见过他们已经和
question D well and that was a small
问题D很好，那是一个小问题
sampling mmm and question D how does the
采样mmm和问题D如何
counselor know when the formal biblical
辅导员知道什么时候正式的圣经
counseling should end I think these are
咨询应该结束我认为这些是
three good criteria one the presenting
三个好标准一个呈现
problem was solved to the council he is
问题解决了他的理事会
using Scripture to address other issues
用圣经来解决其他问题
in their life in other words it's week
在他们的生活中，换句话说是一周
eight of meeting with this person and
和这个人见面的八个人
they say to you during your counseling
他们在你的咨询期间对你说
meeting oh hey by the way had this big
遇见哦，嘿，顺便说一句这个大
argument with my wife the other day and
前几天和我妻子争吵
that brought up this issue that had been
这提出了这个问题已 被
ongoing for a long time so I searched
持续了很长时间，所以我搜索
the scriptures to try to figure out how
经文试图弄清楚如何
the Bible addressed that issue and also
圣经解决这个问题， 也
how I should discuss it with my wife and
我应该如何与我的妻子讨论呢
how we should make a decision about it I
我们应该如何做出决定呢
hear the Scriptures that I found we had
听到我发现的经文
that conversation here's the decision we
那次谈话是我们的决定
made how did I do well that tells you a
造我是怎么做的很好，告诉你一个
lot that tells you that not only are
不少告诉你，不仅是
they changing and growing and becoming
他们在变化，成长和成长
more like Christ in their presenting
在他们的呈现中更像基督
problem but they're at this point of
问题，但他们就是在这一点上
maturity in their use of the scripture
他们使用经文的成熟度
that they can apply it to other things
他们可以将它应用于其他事物
that tells you you're getting very near
这告诉你，你已经非常接近
the end of their need to meet with you
他们需要与你见面的结束
and then also general consistency in the
然后也是一般的一致性
spiritual disciplines presented during
在这期间提出的精神纪律
counseling so the the two or three
这样的两三个辅导
spiritual disciplines that we've covered
我们所涵盖的精神学科
in detail are they living those out on
详细的是他们生活在那里
their own without help from you so the
他们自己没有你的帮助所以
results the results of God using his
结果上帝用他的结果
word to help people change first in
帮助人们改变的第一句话
response to being born again and being
回应重生和存在
redeemed through the blood of Christ
通过基督的宝血赎回
their response to the gospel and then in
他们对福音的反应然后在
strengthening Christians to do well in
加强基督徒做得好
specific discipleship they've replaced
他们取代了具体的门徒训练
sin with righteousness or they've grown
正义的罪或他们已经成长
in their understanding of the word so
在他们对这个词的理解中
now they're living the word in a
现在他们正在生活中
practical way and the things that they
实用的方式和他们的事情
were struggling with they're dealing
正在与他们交易挣扎
with trials in a way that is courageous
以勇敢的方式进行审判
and boldly honoring God and then also in
大胆荣耀神，然后还
the general discipleship they have a few
一般的门徒训练他们有一些
of these practices in place and they're
这些做法到位了，他们是
headed toward more of those it's so
走向更多那样的人
exciting because the end result is once
令人兴奋，因为最终结果是一次
again you've seen God do what only he
再一次， 你看到上帝只做他的事
could do he he changed a Christians life
他能改变基督徒的生活吗？
through his word and so the graduating
通过他的话等毕业
counsel II is prepared for a growing
律师II准备成长
life with God in the context of the
在上下文中与上帝同在
local church
当地的教堂
you
您